we have a lot to talk about haven't
talked in a long time we have so much to
talk about hey where's my chat this
Austrian chat okay there we go
no viewers all right
Goyo welcome to the stream hopefully
we'd have the bandwidth okay guys okay
we have a few things to address as soon
as we get a couple of viewers in here so
the compressor works I fixed that we can
go over I was being stupid with the
automatic coder
I was trying to encode infinite
precision but you don't you need
infinite precision like it's fine just
represent it as 32 bits key inside the
precision doesn't have to be perfect
just the same on encode and decode um so
it's still saying we have zero viewers
let's give people a little bit of time
to get in here I start talking some shit
just we're talking ship tonight remember
how I said these things we're gonna go
we're gonna go we're gonna be good and
they're gonna not talk shit well guess
what we're talking shit tonight maybe
well we'll see if we can make the
compressor be gzipped oh no I'm not in
Jersey man yo what's up no I'm not in
Jersey all right guys you don't know
where I am it's all my shirt I'm in
Langkawi Island Malaysia Langkawi Island
Malaysia now is shit-talking time
tonight no no we'll do some coding too
but it's a little bit hard to do coding
because guys I've fallen on rough times
I've fallen off times and I'm extremely
poor
I'm extremely poor all right so this is
all the written gets I also have 100
more Ringgits but otherwise this is
what's left of my money um so we're out
of money um this room tonight
cost me 48 ringgit it was 38 ringin on
the website but if you're not Malaysian
you have to pay the ten ringgit tourism
tax um you can donate to be regular
twitch you can a subscriber you can give
me money so the only this is a great
room
um I'll show you guys the room I know I
don't usually do this but you know this
one this one will make an exception so
here's the room um it's a great room
except for the fact that and anyone
who's traveled in Southeast Asia knows
this
this is fan room this is not aircon room
thank you for subscribing thank you
the UM yeah so I'm in fan room so it's
very hot I'm in Malaysia and tomorrow
I'm going to Thailand I bought zero
hookers on my trip but zero hookers I
did go on dates I bought girls drinks we
should have gotten cheaper drinks in
retrospect because because I'm out of
money um no no I'm not taking my shirt
off today I could take my shirt off but
I kind of like my langkawi malaysia
shirt this shirt cost me ten ringgit
because I wanted to have my laundry done
today which I did which also cost me ten
during it everything in Malaysia costs
money now the other thing that we're
gonna shit talk about is this I don't
usually read the comments on on the
YouTube but
did that this one was the top comment
wait does George really not know what an
integral is and it got 12 up votes guys
this fake news no no no like lick
illegally I really don't think I said
that and we're not going to be able to
have these anymore of comments that I
made are gonna get interpreted out of
context I complained that there was an
integral you know this this just just
the level of a fake news and the
intensity with which which which you
guys will up vote fake news so so okay
um if anyone would like to ask me
questions about integrals I promise you
I haven't learned this stuff recently we
can do this I got a five on BC calc AP
exam when I was when I was fifteen and I
don't really forget much of that I mean
it was pretty new shit I remember how to
press the integral symbol of my ti 89 so
yes I know what an integral is and and
you guys can ask me questions about it
and then I want everybody to go on
YouTube and download that comment B this
is bullshit man are you guys gonna stand
for that big news first you can ask me
first you can you can you know you can
ask me questions right here and chat
about about integrals and in like you
know here's here's here's here's my
interview here's my interview I let's go
wants to ask me integral questions don't
give me like hard bullshit like if you
ask me what the integral of like sine is
it's like negative cosine or something
but is it negative cosine well so an
integral is an area under the curve so
if you think about the integral of sine
here's sine well you really have to talk
about how you wanna how you want to
define that integral but yeah you
probably want it to be your negative
cosine because you wanted to start from
here at minus one so yes the the
integral of sine
cosine what's the integral of an
exponential an integral of like two to
the X well so the integral of e to the X
is of course the same as the derivative
of e to the X which is e to the X I do
love you to the X for that so if that's
what you mean by an exponential if you
ask me what the I don't know if 2 to the
X was I don't know maybe I should know
that what's the integral of 1 the
integral of 1 is X plus C of course
don't forget your plus C's I think
that's right right the integral of 1 is
well yeah so the integral case so if you
think about the line y equals 1 the
integral is going to be X oh yes the
integral of the tangent of sine alright
so I think for that we have to use the
chain rule so yeah ok yeah that that's
that's beyond what I can do what I can
do in my head III don't know what
alabaster integral or judicial a
function is though I have heard that
name before the up votes are going up
fuck you guys you know you know I hate
that fake news man
I hate that fake news so so welcome to
my stream of good I'm glad you're you're
convinced that the derivative of cosine
is minus sine so yeah that's exactly
what I said you can take the - you can
take the minus sign outside and integral
the integral of the derivative of sine
would be cosine if you think like this
slope of sine here is going to be 1 you
can convert the tan to sine cosine and
then do it tangent is sine over cosine
hey guys don't spring fake news if
there's gonna be fake news we can't have
nice things anymore and also please
subscribe to my twitch channel guys this
is all the money I have left in Malaysia
and is why I have fan room and not
aircon room tonight yeah all right all
right
well you know that's the thing you ask
people on the Internet to do something
you're never gonna get that done this
you like you gotta you gotta ask
yourself difficult questions the
integral of e to the X is e to the X
plus C plus C for that wonder then okay
so you can also have you can also have
to have definite integrals where a
definite integral is when you have like
here's your like weird integral e thingy
and then there's like that guy and that
guy and you compute the integral with
that and then do minus the integral of
that and then you don't need a plus C
anymore
if you sedan didn't go but if C
indefinite integral you have to put the
plus C or you get little minus ones on
your math test now guys I have them
let's count my money one ringgit doing
it mmm seven ringgit 57 ringgit and i do
want to make it off Langkawi Island
tomorrow I do want to make it off link
Harry Island tomorrow like you have to
ask yourself tough questions do I drink
the tap water or do we pay to ring it
for ice mountain it's cause to wring it
guys what do you do for money I'm a
cowboy
you can tailor expand oh I guess yeah
and well I should begley know how to do
that you don't think I really know about
Taylor expansions is like that so you
can compute like there's a couple to
compute you can compute sine X that way
and then that so you can get like PI if
you want if you want to do PI there's a
couple Taylor expansions I think there's
the Taylor expansion of e to the X as
well I know the edx thing has like the
factorials or something thank you for
subscribing thank you thank you James
read thank you thunder shots and thank
you a 20-7 TV for subscribing ok so
let's see did you guys actually y'all I
voted that shit y'all up Wow Wow 20 up
let's not thanks twitchy's thanks
twitch's you're all terrible
alright alright umm first
yeah no no no I don't want to have
cholera you know what they say about
penny wise and pound poor you don't want
it you don't want to do shit like that
because yap yap yap yap yap yeah okay
well dude we don't talk about kama on
this stream i remember the basics of
calc nope like my point that I was
trying to get it you know what let's
revisit that integral since we've spent
a lot of time on the integral incident
now um I believe it was used year this
is probably gonna be the last here we go
okay the KT probability of a binary data
sequence is defined as this now what's
the integral of this I don't know I just
the A's and the B's are constant I don't
know what W is a W is this so I plug
this in so now I have like weird PI's in
my integral they write all of this out
and then they just say well here's an
equation for it right like my point is
we could have avoided and in to go there
this sound and the guys I'm amazed that
the internet works here at all I'm gonna
link Aoi Island if you if you're just
tuning in I'm on the link Aoi Island and
fuck you YouTube commenters I don't know
what the integral is but we're not doing
any well we'll do more math questions
you know I always like math questions
cuz it's good a judge you memory keeps
you sharp keeps you ready for the world
ahead don't forget your math kids math
super important
all right I've been drinking his ice
mountain water all night
should we have a tea should we have this
tea it's a little late for tea but
should we have the tea either way I got
a pee so I'm gonna go do that and then
we're gonna get the coating on Langkawi
Island
okay
yeah DEFCON yeah my good that anymore
guys calm a I still exists it's a
company it's out there it's doing
actually really well um my name is
George Hotz I am a person on this stream
we don't talk about comma AI we talk
about fun programming activities thank
you thank you I washed my hands guys
there's no soap yes I didn't use soap
but you know I rinse them off all right
TMI all right so I fixed the arithmetic
coder I'm sorry I did this when you guys
weren't watching I was mad at myself in
the last stream for not being able to
get it to work right so it turns out
like the reason I was trying to use
fractions I did wash my hands and I'm
the reason I was trying to use fractions
because I felt that the precision had to
be infinite but when you work it out the
precision doesn't have to be perfect it
just has to be the same on encode and
decode so you can read what I'm doing
here
this this p0 is out of 256 after you do
this right and then this is a little
cute trick this is a little cute trick
to make it go from 1 to 255 because you
can't predict a probability of 0 or 1
because if you are wrong you have
probability log infinity right so you
always want to leave a little bit of
margin for error and that when you put
upper bound it we can of course encode
things with more precision but I don't
know
that's gonna matter that much so then
this here is you can see what it does it
just subtracts these things as integers
so there's a precision loss here when
you do this but it doesn't matter
because it's identical on I don't have
that keyboard I'm on a 13-inch Mac Pro
sitting on a bed because I don't have a
table in my room online Kerry island so
that's that's the coder okay so you can
see that we're not doing that well in
terms of bytes but at least you have
like a proper test for compressor now so
you know we're compressing the file we
run compressing the file and then we're
checking to make sure if they're the
same please subscribe please donate so I
can afford nicer hotel rooms ever
talking about the fuck Sony man I'm not
talking about the ps3 we code here and
we do math that's what we do on this
stream so I also had context tree
waiting almost entirely wrong the thing
that I wrote was not really context tree
waiting you have to track these two
probabilities P E and P W so one of the
things that really helped me understand
how it works was I read I read some
other implementations so there's this
nice easy to read implementation written
and go except that it gets a horrible it
compresses way worse than gzip so it's a
terrible compressor and then there's
this one which is the authors
implementation and we can we can take a
look at it what I put
[Music]
no this is probably weird to have all
that much closer so yeah this is the
author's implementation but when you
read it there's tons of bullshit like
there's you know there's just bullshit
like these ones aren't that bad but
there's one where it's just arbitrarily
we're gonna find it this stuff is so
it's extremely complicated and looks
like in order to get that loss they
didn't just implement what's in the
paper they do a huge set of hacks I
talked about the most egregious one I
actually mentioned in the readme and
everything for my shed if you remove the
max counts thing so there's this thing
called max counts which if you remove if
you increase it yeah maybe I just did
something wrong but if you increase it
basically if a count exceeds these range
because it doesn't want things to get
small but so I did also check out this
this morning this is Skip CTS so it's
the more advanced one it's the skip
context tree waiting I skip context tree
switching and now I understand what
context free switching means too
it basically just means that this this
idea of context is big in the hotter
prize compressors which means that like
different party it deals with the fact
that sources in reality are non
stationary so if you see that here talks
about stationary sources and the
stationary source means that like
everywhere in the file or in the string
is statistically identical by any sort
of test to do should we have the tea
guys sure we have the tea I don't know
if we get a subscriber in the next two
minutes we'll have the tea otherwise we
wanted the team
sounds good so one of the things I think
we can do that's really going to improve
things is if we add support in the nodes
for well so they're these skip contracts
tree switching implementation I read
looked a lot simpler
there's a recent extension of context
tree waiting that and I'm curious what
these theoretical properties are because
that's what they said about cgw I'm not
quote did you subscribe you have to
subscribe gonna have the tea you know
then we're gonna get a better stream
otherwise we're not gonna get as good of
his stream um okay he's right you want
to sit here for like an hour while I try
to figure out like which box and haratz
from which box and who has ownership of
the pointer I mean we could do that I've
tried to code and rusty takes me forever
it's not exciting to watch but yeah so
what we can look at tonight is let's do
symbols
okay
dirty that crap I was doing with all the
notes
Wow looks okay except we're gonna have
to change this too
so I'm just refactoring this to allow
multiple symbols I'm more than two we're
gonna see cuz I have a theory that just
like it's only really slow because we're
doing everything in terms of bits so if
we switch it to do things in terms of
bytes
I think things might work a lot better
yeah so here we're gonna need something
slightly different
[Music]
I don't need to right here we want to
use tpw outside so this PW is the
weighted probability it inherits from
the previous one so that should work out
to be pretty much the same
[Music]
this indices must be integrals or slices
none type
should be okay
Oh X is somehow none
sometime in is on none Wow don't you
man domain error
[Music]
you probably would this
like that being too close to zero or
something
normally subscribe no to100 Sabbatini
you know you know I look a little good
guys this is all the money I have
alright I live in I live in fan room
what about while I'm not having the tea
guys the tea costs money too
everything costs money
it's truly code better okay math domain
y0
and zero
how did that Oh
I am log addicts that seems right
and it's not none
we do that subtly send over bitch
okay
[Music]
when is that even different
basically it's a root node we want to
use that that's not it
okay let's think about when it would
predict a zero
so the way this thing actually works and
this is a trick I stole from the go
paper but it's also used oh the Python
MC AXI ttw is just it's just wrong big
numbers they're not too large
so what this does is gets the likelihood
of the tree and I had to fake zero to it
and then it gets the likelihood of the
tree again it seems like that's doing
nothing
oh no that's okay
self-taught parent equals parent know
itself that's fine
find prove exclave that's right
crazy
and it's gonna fix it
you can print this crap again yeah okay
so I think the problem was just that I
wasn't creating those notes don't really
matter it actually seems to do better if
I create those notes no maybe not
it doesn't do better take that one back
but yeah the promise is no way to really
on create the notes so when I call
reverse it doesn't remove the node can I
make it remove the note not really known
as it's done and find so you okay it's a
tree it's like a suffix tree and what
this is doing by the way you guys can
find all of this code on my github
github geo hot twitch cgw I mean the
problem of compression is always asking
the question given the previous symbols
what's the probability looks like the
probability distribution the next symbol
you can answer that question well you
can compress
I can't even have the fan and the fan
room on because it messes with our apps
yet which makes you wonder about the UH
the Wi-Fi gets worse when I turn the fan
on which makes you wander
makes you wonder a little device print
statements are definitely okay okay so
that's Oh scared me
it's doing a create and that is good
it's probably slightly suboptimal
because really we want to run create the
node after we're done with it well let's
see I will deal with this later let's
just first see if we can do a lot better
so we're gonna try to compress are using
bytes instead of bits as contexts one
can see there he's gonna want that
underneath bite Jen I mean that's just
the file itself right
reasonable must index out of range
oh yes that's right we have to say for
colder no not for the cold air there's a
no I'm actually
they create no we want to say symbol
equals B sex
well I think that's right
definitely not right with the encoder
[Music]
yeah okay so
the problem now is we don't have to
anymore
thank you hacks feel for subscribing
thank you she would drink the tea now no
I will drink the tea tomorrow the tea is
for tomorrow we have a lot to do
tomorrow we have to go to Highland
tomorrow we're going to Thailand I
wonder if people hear me what they think
what if they think I'm talking so I was
thought Peter I said two minutes okay so
we have a little problem now we're
[Music]
basically so
I mean technically we only have to do
symbols - one by
see the problem
well this is also useless
that's not a probability what the hell
kind of numbers that
well this isn't right anymore this is
actually won over self dot symbols
I know it's too small
I don't know what that 25 is no I think
that point 5 is different
yeah this isn't right
no let's not skip CTS it's just
context-free waiting it's the one that's
based on this isn't right
okay so those are all close to one
garbage
yeah
so we have to figure out how to do that
the KT estimator for things that are
non-binary Skip CTS might actually have
an implementation of this it's going to
take a look
it's fast math
Oh
long gasp then we don't use numpy so hey
it's numpy I hate time
yeah whatever it is we believe the numpy
so yeah I'm doing all the probabilities
and logs because they get big and you
want to remain numerically stable um did
that be cool didn't copy that actually
be interesting I'm curious to read that
code let's read this code quickly swap
them okay I've seen this before
it was like some identity with logs
Oh
I'll see if this is all this fancy shit
by default it uses a DeRusha lay
estimator with a perks prior alright if
the next YouTube commenters would like
to make fun of me for not knowing what
those things are that's okay but don't
tell me I don't know high school now I
was tricked
estimator prior know that I'm not
triggered anymore
I'm only triggered when you didn't mean
to trigger be if you mean to trigger me
I'm not really triggered I'm like I know
trolls and other troll
hmm
what is this thing like this this just
looks beautiful this coat it's kind of
nice
no not that beautiful he looks simple
anyway
okay so they're not using KT estimator
they're using different thing
oh no guys
what doesn't work did you know that
because this isn't correct
there's the other implementation
yeah by AXI there's another
implementation maybe they have the right
thing here
this code i thought was pretty ugly
you know this only works for zeros and
ones
see that's the log something but that's
why it's been awfully unstable because
they didn't do that other stuff
you know no hacks if I doesn't get
banned because he has star next to his
name
and when you have a star next to your
name it's like it's like discrimination
you get away with stuff because you have
a star next your name and you're better
than people who don't have a star next
you guys know how to start works right
because I only have 57 ringgit okay
can't say too lousy about 57 wearing it
what if I get robbed
Oh watch out now Malaysia that we saved
country
I was sketched out by this girl and we
won't go into that story but Malaysia is
a super safe country you always ask
always with the why the why the why oh
it's a dumb question
no no I'm not going into that story not
enough but oh thank you thank you for
watching an ad thank you um okay so
unfortunately this one doesn't work for
multiple stuff and the other one uses
some other crazy stuff that I don't
understand tutorials that's that I wrote
I wrote a little I wrote a little
compressor that uses the CTS
implementation just to test the to test
the number of bits and yeah so it seems
to encode it in under three dozen bytes
so this is the best one
now Malaysia's are super safe country
guys so well it's really it's a really a
good story
yes I wrote this just a little thing
that uses this thingy which is allegedly
good but maybe you wait this gonna make
sense oh that gives me the log
probability of C okay I understand
yeah so I can again iterate over all
them to do that
well what's in the docks on the docks
any good
whether I like these people they include
their reference Python implementation
because no one implement stuff and see
on the first try
why do that makes it work in Python
first
all my boat buying plans I forgot all
about that forgot all about that
all right I think there's things that
I'm gonna have to learn about this
version works with large alphabets
so probably what they're doing I mean
yeah it does look like they're using a
kt estimate all right like they don't
talk about it anywhere I just use Bayes
rule here I mean if I have a prior I
think the only question is like what's
my prior right so this this this update
can be replaced by Bayes rule
I think that's effectively kind of what
it is right cuz I'm subtracting over the
sum of all possible
we don't talk about the past even if
you're a subscriber we only talk about
the future
okay so instead of using a KT estimator
it's using a derisively estimator
okay it's a multivariate generalization
of the beta distribution so the beta
distribution is what's discussed in the
other paper
this talks about the beta distribution
we should understand what the beta
distribution is
yeah you know what you guys want to
cheat you guys want to use you want to
use there's let's see if we can actually
make it a compressor let's do that first
make sure the lightness is something
reasonable
okay so this actually still doesn't make
this problem trivial even though we're
cheating No
I'm gonna give it the same interface as
the other one the other one is it pretty
good interface I think model of
contextual sequence wall
and that's the interface log prob
I'm gonna get the number of those for
this thing
Oh see look yeah look they do the same
thing have a special symbol call it
starts in them it starts them so they're
actually doing the same trick as I am
here instead of so they're just called
soft up free bags that's right
called context Lance
number of bits like a moron um so you
can think of this as cheating a little
bit you can think of it kinda like i'm
i'm reading i'm using this
implementation but this is actually how
you learn things like try to do things
for yourself struggle to an extent and
then really kind of mesh the two
implementations together it's probably
the most efficient way I've really found
to learn
so if they call Preet with would they
call context I call pre-tax
here we want to say cgw okay I'll make
sure my shit still works self dot
context Lane
I'll spell it right just index out of
rain
yeah that's amazing fighter
so that really shouldn't be global
mmm if you subscribe no I mean I use the
top right as well it's just it's just
hard I know you miss a little bit you
miss a little bit what's down here
it's kind of hard there kind of breaks
the abstraction
it's hacky is still gonna use a ball
ball but
okay
so I mean it's got a shitty compression
ratio but I think it still works
he wrote a test very high quality test
okay let's plug in their model because
they actually understand what a DeRusha
lay estimator and sampler is and stuff
and one day we're gonna understand this
but I think it's less fun to do one two
edge
okay
so
yes
from cts important
and then we will just say cg w equals
all about contextual sequence no okay
so is it called update called up there
where you switch that to bite chance
that this is still wrong let's see if it
works
okay
I was logged problem so in order to
convert a log prob to a real probability
we have to do a map back course
and also probably doesn't have an
attribute notes does it
and we have notes
well look one byte of entropy how did we
do it
okay okay okay we'll move the camera
but no complaining if it's up here all
right a little bit wrong
hmm so it's very slow now see how slow
it is so slow so small oh it takes so
much bites
that's not exactly right it really just
one count yeah yeah every night you do
count times eight so it's number of bits
to encode the bytes is actually correct
I think
thank you thank you for the bet thank
you
okay so now we're doing things at the
fight level we're gonna see if we get
better compression
insanely slow
and what it does compress better
because ratios
yeah such good ratios
you know what I believe a bit is 10
cents large I'm probably wrong
well okay this does a lot better
yeah wow it's getting down to 29% bros
okay
so we have a few problems one everything
is so slow - we're not really encoding
anything make sure that's correct oh
that should be one
you got all posts already say it's
closed
but if it's a proper probability
distribution it has to sum to one don't
get it twisted so sum to one
okay so now we have the problem my
arithmetic coder doesn't support more
than more than a few symbols
maybe the contact shorter seems to make
it faster
and for this
I actually do math dot log - really
stupid eights every one H is measured in
bits here we know that but I can
actually write here as math dialogue -
symbols that'll make that more generic
um if you're looking for recommendations
for for software projects you should buy
a panda and you should have features to
the firmware wait but that sucks still
that's crappy
mostly that still works with CGS equals
false
what really oh well so I didn't listen
when it's a log drop did I
I thought it was faster but actually
this place is not the cloud as hot as
fuck and there's no air conditioning but
that's just because I'm cheap
and the rs80 today's come ok so just in
penang penang had good food and now I'm
in blink owie and food I mean it's not
bad but I might go out buy a fish no not
taking my shirt off guys as you missed
that was there was one shirt off stream
and that was a special stream and you
guys missed it I mean if you missed it
if you were here for the shirt off
stream and then congratulations who saw
the shirt off stream
where is your post box
try contact me I'm 16
yeah Penang had great food I missed the
Penang food
I might go spend my last 57 Ringgits on
a fish I might
all right let's come on to win the hotel
[Music]
yeah others peeing on the street that's
right we're in a small room together
guys chill relax you're all here with me
you're all welcome to link our yeah you
know when you're hurt peeing yeah this
is a real shit man like I would have
closed the door but like I'll show you
guys the door I'll show you guys the
door I'm like I don't know if you can
close
No so that's bad
this one doesn't even do better than
guys yeah yeah Malaysia just does that
to you just start out you know
but after all this this one has a crappy
ratio to wait
I mean does worse their worst rooms this
isn't even the bottom
okay so that race just kind of garbage
as well interesting and maybe the CTW
isn't very good
what is that
does random need to be banned or any my
mods in here
there's my mother
this guy's is banned if I can ban him
not know how to ban him mod you you're
subbed how do I do that
just salt I wouldn't mind you but
Oh exclamation point mod username okay
now think that worked
oh I didn't slash mod dude swear if you
got to subscribe if you want to be mod
just all tasks first and he's a
subscriber so you know that's rule yeah
it's probably slash I don't know what's
up with these exclamation points
congratulations you are moderator um
okay well why does this do better
yes I did give it a context line 232 but
it might also have to do with the fact
that I generate all the all the things
which I think I have to
but that's actually worse oh not the CGS
is Fosters
ya know I'm starting to have my doubts
about this algorithm being very good I
don't know why all these people hype it
out through all these papers hyping up
this stupid algorithm and then like you
write it I'm like this is not that good
no the only proof I have that it isn't
all terrible is there is the CGW
baseline and they did better than they
do better than Jesus this code is
actually a compressor that does better
than Jesus that skips egw to skip CTX
thing Wow
there's people here listen to people -
yeah the skips easiest thing I mean it
just doesn't seem better when I generate
all the probabilities of all the symbols
so it was it was sneaking information it
right like once I actually compute all
this
the ratio seems garbage this isn't
better okay
well that doesn't really work see that's
the thing unless you actually have
produced to file and then D compress the
file you do have no idea your compressor
gonna have all kinds of bugs like you
can't trust these probabilities remember
when I trusted the probabilities and I
thought that we already beat gzip and it
was a lie now this one actually does
beat gzip oh I really don't want to know
about your pants but this one also has a
whole lot of garbage
it just has hacks I mean if I wanted to
write compressors with hacks I'm sure I
could write compressors with hacks but I
wanted to write a theoretically good
compressor okay well it's good to know
that there's not a working there's not a
good Python implementation with this
anywhere and you saw you see the ratio
here it's it's worse than gzip
hmm well let's let's set some reasonable
settings let's get a reasonable
compression with mine and then toasts
let's get a reasonable compression and
call it a day
I think it actually does better with
slightly less
[Music]
even better nobody can't keep getting
that I mean it eventually will exceed
[Music]
sixteen seems pretty good even better
not worse okay 16's let's do a final
compression with this thing it isn't
working compressor it does work it will
produce something
you gotta lock the door bro mmm now the
worst though is the touts tellers gotta
watch out for towers man I'll try to
tout and sell you stuff
my compressors as good as theirs almost
there is go-go bar when we go to go
check my Oh symbol that's before
I say
okay it gets about 50% compression
ratios and takes a long-ass time um in
the future anybody who talks about the
ps3 is banned the ps3 is a bad topic or
Sony fuck Sony
so our moderators if you could in the
future nobody cares
don't know I don't punch people they
don't know the rules you know you gotta
be ferry alright don't don't go in some
Soni coming after me
let's gather them but it's just don't
actually anymore
okay it's a working compressor but I
think we are all disappointed with the
performance
yeah
and you guys can confirm that you can
defend week four and and look for Dec
and they're the same but the ratio is
kind of shitty because the model is not
that good even their model was still
getting doing worse than gzip the only
one I've seen this better is this cgw
baseline which is written by the authors
of the paper by
maybe I think I'm in a meeting maybe
that's what people think when they made
me talk we'r disappoints weird
disappoints um you know you guys if the
compressor was good it was a good
compressor I was gonna write it and rust
thank you graduation Reagan Reagan oh
thank you for subscribing so I think
that kind of wraps up which CDW unless
we get a lot better unless we figure out
that we're doing something wrong if
somebody out there can find a better
implementation of this stuff that does
like better than mine I'd be impressed I
mean I'm sure there's like subtle ways
it can do better but there's a little
bug in mine too there's a little bug
where it doesn't uncreate the node if it
creates the nodes
ya know wouldn't you like to see me code
and rust sometimes sometimes it lazy yes
what about basic probabilities
completely theory it's got like only a
few axioms I think then calm our graph
is actually the one who
yeah
No also if you haven't checked it out
definitely check out quantum computing
since Democritus it goes into how
quantum stuff is just l to quantum
probabilities amplitudes of the l2 norm
of probability it's pretty cool yeah if
you want to do that I don't know it just
seemed boring and a lot like a lot of
tedious work and it's not like I'm not
gonna learn anything doing it I mean I'm
sure I learned stuff but it's not really
what I'm interested in anymore I'm doing
a lot more math stuff lately which is
why I was particularly offended by the
integral thing I read this book it was
okay
the first the first one was pretty good
it's like three lectures by mr. Chayton
guy shape this constant
I'll get a lot of people on tonight's
stream yeah sorry twitch CW didn't work
that well
let's add an old mountain to read me
it is a working
no I'll say maybe it
no I don't know I don't recommend shit
for people man do whatever seems fun you
know wine carry hey well so I'm not
gonna say this tool mildly but don't
come to langkawi okay
I would avoid langkawi but Thailand lies
ahead let's take a look at the map here
I am in link Aoi on sinning Beach
tomorrow we take an overpriced taxi to
kueh and then we take it over priced
ferry to probably koala Perlis
and then we get on a train and we go to
Thailand will decide halfway through
whether we want to stop should we stop
at the coast I worry that the cozaar
gonna be just like link Aoi but talk in
which case we can skip the coast
definitely skip Phuket
Sarat to me I just read the beach that's
what I did for the last two days I read
the beach not that not that not the
movie it's a pretty good book and I kind
of enjoyed it it's trash it's like it's
like easy to read trash but no this is
enjoyable Bangkok yeah and I think this
might be this might be it first dreams
for a bet unless I have something new
and good there's a chance I'll do one
more cgw stream if I figure out how to
actually fix this thing but so we'll
take a quick overview of what it is if
anybody wants to look through it
basically the idea of a compressor is
you have a you have a model and you have
a coda so the model says the model
answers the question
given the probability actually yeah you
know basically you want to ask the
question what is probability of symbol X
given symbol 1 through X minus 1 or
really suppose there's much model
answers
and then we have the code now what the
coder does is simple arithmetic code
there two symbols what what the coder
then does if you know this probability
right so if you knew exactly what the
next symbol was going to be you wouldn't
need you wouldn't need a coder right you
could just run them all on the model
would generate your whole text but you
don't know exactly what the next symbol
is gonna be you know with some
probability what the next sentence gonna
be so let's say you're 80% sure the next
symbol is going to be a 1 and your 20%
Shore therefore the 20% sure it's gonna
be a 0 if you're in a two symbol
alphabet right so now we can do math log
2 of 0.8 oh wait no that's
- lot log - we need Python 3 and then so
if we yeah so if if the next let's think
about this for a sec
this is a little bit what trip you have
last time but but basically if you know
your distribution better than if you're
a 50% chance for each if it's 50/50 oh
it's 1 / ok if it's 50/50 then it takes
one bit of information to cope right
because it's 50/50 right but if you know
that it's point 8 it takes point 3 bits
of information to go point 3 2 bits of
information but if you get it wrong and
it actually turns out to be the point 2
then it takes 2 point 3 bits of it it's
all right because there's no free lunch
so if your model is wrong it takes more
than one bit to code that bit and if
your model is right it takes less than
one bit to code that back so the
theoretical limit given your model is
computed right here in CDW your
theoretical limit is computed here so -
that log tail so I think I add I just do
this see how that works so it's so the
identity right so that's theoretical the
arithmetic coder gets really close to
the optimal in fact the only place where
it's wrong is is my floating-point
rounding errors and my moving the
probability is off of off of the rails
because of course if you predict
something with probability 1 it takes no
bits at all to encode but if you predict
something with probability 0 you get a
math domain error so don't do that
avoid math domain heiress oh I think my
chat froze
let me go to look I was educational guys
who enjoyed who enjoyed the actual
educational segments
no no what my chat one it's going guys
it's been
let me try closing the gaps
all right we'll go on hold on cell for a
little bit I don't know how much cell
but my phone was acting up okay thank
you thank you everybody thank you I see
all the Me's I see all the Me's I got my
chat back all right
that's today's stream don't have a talk
shit about me not in all in high school
mouth remember the ps3 is a ban topic
from this channel and this might be the
last race for a while thank you for a
beautiful Langkawi Island don't come
here promise fish people like to rip you
off all right all right you want to do a
little reading all right
well we'll do a little reading we'll do
a little reading before we go I've been
reading this my friend said it to me
this is actually the public domain book
this is published by the CIA so I was
reading this
but what do I do I don't talk while I
read I just sit there there are some
cool pictures in this book though yeah
from the CIA man you know the CIA
actually put out a good book
improving intelligence analysis at CIA
they open sourced it for some reason
which I thought was mad cool in my
American tax dollars at work guys that
kind of Miss America who misses America
kind of Miss America this isn't the
cloud
it's called the psychology of
intelligence analysis as soon as you
read a log
I'm on chapter three about memory oh
yeah that's that I was reading I'll
bring my cow
oh yes the bucket what I think is left
it's nice it's nice that can be compiled
nobody should be coding and see anymore
she's a terrible language you see you
know it's just nothing man
any of the books I recommend no come on
computing systemic Rattus breed that I
see only or to spell I gotta go I got I
gotta go buy fish